{"test_questions": [[{"question": "What is the color code for a 220  5% resistor?", "opta": "Red, Red, Brown, Gold", "optb": "Orange, Orange, Black, Gold", "optc": "Red, Red, Black, Gold", "optd": "Red, Red, Brown, Silver", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Resistor colour coding series:\n\nBlack   0 \nBrown   1 \nRed     2 \nOrange  3 \nYellow  4 \nGreen   5 \nBlue    6 \nViolet  7  \nGray    8   \nWhite   9 \nNone    20% \nSilver  10% \nGold    5% \n\nTherefore Red, Red, Brown, Gold \n           2    2    101    5% \n\n = 22 x 10 = 220 ohm 5% (tolerance)."}, {"question": "If 60 J of energy are available for every 15 C of charge, what is the voltage?", "opta": "4 V", "optb": "60 V", "optc": "15 V", "optd": "0.25 V", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An atom's atomic number is determined by the number of:", "opta": "neutrons minus protons", "optb": "protons", "optc": "electrons", "optd": "neutrons", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A voltage will influence current only if the circuit is:", "opta": "open", "optb": "insulated", "optc": "high resistance", "optd": "closed", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which resistive component is designed to be temperature sensitive?", "opta": "Thermistor", "optb": "Rheostat", "optc": "Potentiometer", "optd": "Photoconductive cell", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The battery symbol is:", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What type of switch is this?", "opta": "push button", "optb": "SPST", "optc": "DPDT", "optd": "SPDT", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Primary batteries, unlike secondary batteries, may be:", "opta": "charged once", "optb": "used once", "optc": "recharged over and over", "optd": "stored indefinitely", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Primary batteries (disposable batteries), which are designed to be used once and discarded when they are exhausted.\n\nSecondary batteries (rechargeable batteries), which are designed to be recharged and used multiple times."}, {"question": "In practical applications, battery voltage:", "opta": "is restored as soon as disconnect occurs", "optb": "is lowered as the load increases", "optc": "may be stored indefinitely", "optd": "will be reduced to zero as power is drawn", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The negative and positive charge symbols are assigned (in that order) to the:", "opta": "proton and electron", "optb": "electron and proton", "optc": "atom and nucleus", "optd": "electron and element", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A voltmeter is used:", "opta": "to measure current", "optb": "in series with the circuit", "optc": "in parallel with the circuit", "optd": "to measure coulombs", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the current in a circuit equals 0 A, it is likely that the", "opta": "voltage is too high", "optb": "resistance is too low", "optc": "circuit has a short", "optd": "circuit is open", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Current equals:", "opta": "", "optb": "coulombs \u00d7 time", "optc": "", "optd": "voltage \u00d7 time", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are the unit and symbol for current?", "opta": "Ampere, A", "optb": "Coulomb, I", "optc": "Ampere, Q", "optd": "Ampere, I", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which part of an atom has no electrical charge?", "opta": "Electron", "optb": "Neutron", "optc": "Proton", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which voltage source converts chemical energy to electrical energy?", "opta": "Electrical generator", "optb": "Battery", "optc": "Solar cell", "optd": "Electronic power supply", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An example of potential energy is:", "opta": "tea-kettle steam", "optb": "a moving vehicle", "optc": "the sun", "optd": "a battery", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If 40 C of charge flow past a point in 20 s, what is the current?", "opta": "2 A", "optb": "0.5 A", "optc": "20 A", "optd": "40 A", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Batteries differ from fuel cells in that", "opta": "a battery is a closed system", "optb": "a battery uses hydrogen and oxygen to create electricity", "optc": "a battery uses a polymer electrolyte membrane", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The removal of a non-neutral subatomic particle converts the atom into a:", "opta": "charged ion", "optb": "nucleus", "optc": "heavier element", "optd": "compound", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One coulomb passing a point in one second is one:", "opta": "ampere", "optb": "volt", "optc": "ohm", "optd": "charge", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In which states may matter may be found?", "opta": "solid, liquid, or mineral", "optb": "solid, gas, or liquid", "optc": "mineral, gas, or liquid", "optd": "plastic, solid, or gas", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Material that consists of a mixture of elements is considered to be:", "opta": "an element", "optb": "an ion", "optc": "a compound", "optd": "a molecule", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many valence shell electrons are there in semiconductor atoms?", "opta": "16", "optb": "8", "optc": "4", "optd": "2", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When considering conventional current versus electron current flow:", "opta": "electron current flow came first", "optb": "protons move in conventional current flow", "optc": "conventional current flow came first", "optd": "the direction of current is the same in both methods", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which unit of charge contains 6.25 \u00d7 1018 electrons?", "opta": "An ampere", "optb": "A coulomb", "optc": "A volt", "optd": "A joule", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A switch is a device that:", "opta": "short circuits complex circuits", "optb": "holds a fuse", "optc": "has double poles", "optd": "opens or completes a current path", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The term used to designate electrical pressure is:", "opta": "voltage", "optb": "current", "optc": "resistance", "optd": "conductance", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which electronics material opposes the movement of free electrons?", "opta": "Conductor", "optb": "Insulator", "optc": "Semiconductor", "optd": "Element", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Current is considered as the movement of:", "opta": "electrons", "optb": "protons", "optc": "charge", "optd": "nuclei", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A lead-acid battery is an example of a", "opta": "solar cell", "optb": "fuel cell", "optc": "primary battery", "optd": "secondary battery", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The charge of one coulomb is equal to:", "opta": "6.24 x 10\u221218 electrons", "optb": "one ampere", "optc": "one second", "optd": "6.24 x 1018 electrons", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A basic electric circuit is made up of what components?", "opta": "A load, a resistor, and a conductive path for current", "optb": "A voltage source, a load, and a conductive path for current", "optc": "A voltage source, a conductive path for current, and a battery", "optd": "A conductive path for current, a battery, and a copper wire", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An ammeter is used to measure", "opta": "voltage", "optb": "current", "optc": "resistance", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the name of the pressure that moves electrons in a closed circuit?", "opta": "amperes", "optb": "ohms", "optc": "voltage", "optd": "coulombs", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is a characteristic of a secondary cell?", "opta": "rechargeability", "optb": "not rechargeable", "optc": "a dry cell", "optd": "non-liquid", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are the basic building blocks that all matter is composed of?", "opta": "electrons, neutrons, and protons", "optb": "two protons for each neutron", "optc": "two protons for each electron", "optd": "electrons, neutrons, and charged ions", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a fluid system is compared to an electrical system, the fluid pump will correspond to a:", "opta": "conductor", "optb": "lamp", "optc": "battery", "optd": "insulator", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An element is a substance that is:", "opta": "varied throughout the entire piece", "optb": "used only in electronics", "optc": "electrically charged", "optd": "found only in its pure form", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Current is:", "opta": "the presence of a positive charge", "optb": "the abundance of electrons", "optc": "the movement of electrons", "optd": "the repulsion of electrons", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What do you call a diagram that shows the electrical connections of a circuit's components?", "opta": "A schematic diagram", "optb": "A pictorial diagram", "optc": "A block diagram", "optd": "An electrical diagram", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A short circuit will have:", "opta": "a small current flow", "optb": "a large current flow", "optc": "no current flow", "optd": "some current flow", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The basic difference between a fuse and a circuit breaker is", "opta": "a fuse is slower", "optb": "a fuse is reusable", "optc": "a circuit breaker is reusable", "optd": "a circuit breaker is more reliable", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is the smallest?", "opta": "atom", "optb": "proton", "optc": "neutron", "optd": "electron", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A secondary cell generates dc via chemical activity; a primary cell generates dc:", "opta": "electrically", "optb": "thermally", "optc": "optically", "optd": "chemically", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements is true?", "opta": "Unlike charges repel and like charges attract.", "optb": "Like charges repel and unlike charges attract.", "optc": "Unlike charges attract and like charges attract.", "optd": "Like charges repel and unlike charges repel.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If an electrical system is compared to a fluid system, the electrical current corresponds to the:", "opta": "pressure", "optb": "pump", "optc": "water wheel", "optd": "water flow", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}